A Guide to the Ludwell Family Papers, 1676-1879
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg
Ludwell Family Papers, 1676-1879.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 65.8
10 items.
Ludwell Family.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 1965.
Alternative Form
Also available on microfilm (M-1557)
Scope and Content Information
Papers associated with the Ludwell family of Virginia, including a duplicate of Thomas Ludwell's will, November 10, 1676; a power of attorney from Alexander Culpeper and Margaret, Lady Culpeper, to Philip Ludwell, November 18, 1688; an early copy of Alexander Culpeper's will of November 29, 1691; a lease of land in Surry County, Va., from Samuel Potts to Philip Ludwell, November 1, 1704; deeds to land in England; a deed to land in and around Williamsburg, Va., from William and Hannah Ludwell Lee to Arthur Lee and Fleming Pinkston, January 9, 1771; claims of Samuel Page's heirs for shipping losses to the French; and a printed Ludwell genealogy.
Arrangement
Chronological.
Index Terms
Family Names:
Ludwell family.
Persons:
Culpeper, Alexander.; Culpepr, Margaret.; Lee, Arthur, 1740-1792.; Lee, Hannah Ludwell, d. 1784.; Lee, William, 1739- 1795.; Ludwell, Philip, 1672-1727.; Ludwell, Thomas, 1628-1678.; Page, Samuel.; Pinkston, Fleming.; Potts, Samuel.
Genre and Form Terms:
Deeds--Virginia--Surry County--18th century.; Deeds--Virginia--Williamsburg--18th century.; Indentures--Virginia--James City County--18th century.; Powers of attorney--17th century.; Wills--17th century.
Geographical Names:
Virginia--Genealogy.
Contents List
- Copy of Will of Thomas Ludwell, leaving L30 to Bruton Parish, Virginia, to build a church, 10 November 1676.
- Lady Margaret Culpeper, Katherine Culpeper, Alexander Culpeper, Power of Attorney to Philip Ludwell, 18 December 1689.
- Copy of Will of Alexander Culpeper giving his 1/6 of the Culpeper (Fairfax) lands in Virginia to Lady Margaret Culpeper, 29 November 1691.
- Deed of Samuel Potts of London to Philip Ludwell of the tract called the Collidge Land in Surry County, Virginia. Recorded, 1 December 1704.
- Deed of John Birch to James Barrett and John Smart of lands in England, 19 August 1726.
- Deed of Release. Mary King and John Sampson of various lands in England, 18 March 1739.
- Indenture of William Lee and Hannah Philippa Ludwell Lee to Arthur Lee and Fleming Pinkston of lands. Recorded, James City County, 12 August 1771. 1 small attachment, 9 January 1771.
- Copy of above indenture of William Lee and Hannah Phillipa Ludwell Lee to Arthur Lee and Fleming Pinkston of lands, 9 January 1771.
- Settlement. William Lee Esq. & Hannah Philippa Ludwell Lee to Fleming Pinkston. 3 pages plus 1 small attachment dated 25 January 1771. Recorded 11 August 1771, 10 January 1771.
- Claim of heirs of Samuel Page for shipping losses to the French in 1799 and 1800, 8 December 1828.